Support Admin Watch on kissasia.cam or kisskh.org
دعم المشرف شاهد على kissasia.cam أو kisskh.org
"The Secret of Girls" (Episode 10)
"سر الفتيات" (الحلقة العاشرة)
Do you think I'm ignorant?
هل تعتقد أنني جاهل؟
What's wrong?
ما هو الخطأ؟
It's fine.
إنه بخير.
Mom.
أم.
Why don't you reply to my messages?
لماذا لا ترد على رسائلي؟
How can I reply to you?
كيف يمكنني الرد عليك؟
You just come back for money.
لقد عدت فقط من أجل المال.
Right?
يمين؟
I called you asking to give me some money, and you didn't answer me.
لقد اتصلت بك أطلب منك أن تعطيني بعض المال، ولم تجيبني.
So I came back.
لقد عدت إذن.
You doing well at your job out in the world?
هل تقوم بعمل جيد في وظيفتك خارج العالم؟
Running back home asking for money.
العودة إلى المنزل وطلب المال.
But I scrimp and I save every month.
لكنني أقتصد وأوفر كل شهر.
I gave you my whole paycheque.
لقد أعطيتك راتبي كاملا.
You said you would save it for me,
لقد قلت أنك ستحفظه لي،
so I came back to ask you for money because I had an emergency.
لذا عدت لأطلب منك المال لأنني كنت في حالة طارئة.
Doesn't your money belong to the family?
هل أموالك ملك للعائلة؟
Look at you.
أنظر إليك.
From childhood to adulthood
من الطفولة إلى البلوغ
I provided you with food, drink and education.
لقد وفرت لك الطعام والشراب والتعليم.
What part of the money you give is yours?
ما هو الجزء من المال الذي تعطيه لك؟
Go ahead and tell me.
اذهب وأخبرني.
Let me tell you.
دعني أخبرك.
There is no money left.
لم يتبقى أي مال.
Even you ask me for it, there's none.
حتى لو طلبته مني، لن أجده.
Where is there none left?
أين لم يبق أحد؟
Your little brother is in a relationship.
أخوك الصغير في علاقة.
They plan to get married next year.
إنهم يخططون للزواج العام المقبل.
So we have to buy a house.
لذلك يتعين علينا شراء منزل.
Your father and I have taken out all our savings.
لقد أخرجنا أنا وأبوك كل مدخراتنا.
It's still not enough for the down payment.
لا يزال هذا غير كاف للدفعة الأولى.
Adding your little bit of cash,
إضافة القليل من النقود الخاصة بك،
we can barely put an offer in on the house.
بالكاد يمكننا تقديم عرض على المنزل.
What money could we have left?
ما هو المبلغ المتبقي لدينا؟
Buying a house?
شراء منزل؟
Yes.
نعم.
Every man has to buy a house to start a family.
يجب على كل رجل أن يشتري منزلاً ليبدأ تكوين أسرة.
Otherwise, where will the children live in the future?
وإلا فأين سيعيش الأطفال في المستقبل؟
Do you think everyone is the same as you?
هل تعتقد أن الجميع مثلك؟
Tell me.
أخبرني.
I introduced you to so many people.
لقد قدمتك للعديد من الأشخاص.
You didn't even go to meet them.
ولم تذهب حتى لمقابلتهم.
You didn't get married.
لم تتزوج.
If you got married earlier and had a dowry, we wouldn't have been so strapped for cash.
لو تزوجت مبكرا وكان لديك مهر، لما كنا بحاجة إلى المال.
And that house we got,
وهذا البيت الذي حصلنا عليه
we have to pay 4000 yuan back every month for the loan.
علينا أن ندفع 4000 يوان شهريًا للقرض.
You only give back 3,000 yuan.
أنت تعطي فقط 3000 يوان.
It's not even enough to pay back the loan.
إنه ليس كافيا حتى لسداد القرض.
How about this,
ماذا عن هذا؟
save a little more each month.
وفر مبلغًا إضافيًا قليلًا كل شهر.
Get up to 4,000 yuan.
احصل على ما يصل إلى 4000 يوان.
If it's not enough, your father and I will make up the rest.
إذا لم يكن ذلك كافيا، فسوف نقوم أنا وأبوك بتعويض الباقي.
It's almost enough.
إنه يكفي تقريبا.
By the way.
بالمناسبة.
This doesn't even include the bride price.
وهذا لا يشمل حتى مهر العروس.
What else is there for me to save?
ماذا بقي لي أن أحفظ؟
Don't eat out a couple times in a month.
لا تأكل خارج المنزل عدة مرات في الشهر.
Buy a couple fewer pieces of clothing.
اشتري عددًا أقل من قطع الملابس.
You can easily save 500 yuan.
يمكنك توفير 500 يوان بسهولة.
What do you mean you can't save?
ماذا تقصد بأنك لا تستطيع الحفظ؟
I was fired.
لقد تم طردني.
And I'm not going to work.
ولن أعمل.
You two handle the mortgage on your own.
أنتما الاثنان تتعاملان مع الرهن العقاري بنفسكما.
Don't count on me.
لا تعتمد علي.
How can you talk to me like this?
كيف يمكنك التحدث معي بهذه الطريقة؟
I raised you up.
لقد ربيتك.
And you talk to me like this?
وتكلمني بهذه الطريقة؟
I see you for who you are now.
أنا أراك كما أنت الآن.
You are an ungrateful person.
أنت شخص جاحد.
That's your brother.
هذا أخوك.
You don't care about him.
أنت لا تهتم به.
I can't!
لا أستطبع!
What do you mean by that?
ماذا تقصد بذلك؟
You.
أنت.
You always say that I am unfilial.
أنت تقول دائمًا أنني غير بار.
Well what about you?
حسنا ماذا عنك؟
What's wrong with me?
ماذا بي؟
Have you ever fulfilled your responsibilities as a mother?
هل سبق لك أن قمت بواجباتك كأم؟
Have you ever cared about me since I came back?
هل اهتممت بي منذ عودتي؟
Did you ask me why I need the money?
هل سألتني لماذا أحتاج المال؟
Why do you need the money?
لماذا تحتاج المال؟
You're an adult now, aren't you?
لقد أصبحت شخصًا بالغًا الآن، أليس كذلك؟
You have your own way of thinking.
لديك طريقتك الخاصة في التفكير.
Who knows why you need money?
من يعرف لماذا تحتاج إلى المال؟
You gave money to your parents and then came back to ask for it.
لقد أعطيت المال لوالديك ثم عدت لتطلبه.
You can ask others.
يمكنك أن تسأل الآخرين.
Who else has a daughter like you?
من لديه ابنة مثلك؟
Is there anyone like you?
هل يوجد أحد مثلك؟
Say something.
قل شيئا.
How about 4000 yuan?
ماذا عن 4000 يوان؟
I am not filial.
أنا لست بارًا.
I am not worthy of being your daughter.
أنا لا أستحق أن أكون ابنتك.
From now on,
من الآن فصاعدا،
just pretend you never gave birth to me.
فقط تظاهري بأنك لم تلدني أبدًا.
You.
أنت.
What are you talking about.
ماذا تتحدث عنه؟
What are you going to do?
ما كنت تنوي القيام به؟
Hello, doctor.
مرحباً دكتور.
Hello.
مرحبًا.
Could you please have a look?
هل يمكنك من فضلك إلقاء نظرة؟
You can see here.
يمكنك رؤية هنا.
Just here.
هنا فقط.
The tumor diameter is longer than 5 cm.
قطر الورم أطول من 5 سم.
And.
و.
There seems to be lymph node and organ migration occuring.
يبدو أن هناك هجرة للغدد الليمفاوية والأعضاء.
What do you mean?
ماذا تقصد؟
What I mean is...
ما أقصده هو...
judging from the indications and what the CT scan shows,
استناداً إلى المؤشرات وما يظهره التصوير المقطعي المحوسب،
you're already in the late stages of it.
أنت بالفعل في المراحل المتأخرة منه.
Late.
متأخر.
Late stage.
المرحلة المتأخرة.
So...
لذا...
Then...
ثم...
So..
لذا..
How long do you think I will live?
كم تعتقد أنني سأعيش؟
Is there any sort of... treatment plan?
هل هناك أي نوع من خطة العلاج؟
Surgery or...
الجراحة أو...
hospitalization?
الاستشفاء؟
Judging from your course of illness.
انطلاقا من مسار مرضك.
It is impossible to have surgery.
من المستحيل إجراء عملية جراحية.
But you can choose chemotherapy or radiotherapy.
ولكن يمكنك اختيار العلاج الكيميائي أو العلاج الإشعاعي.
If the treatment goes well,
إذا كان العلاج يسير بشكل جيد،
you might have an extra few months.
ربما يكون لديك بضعة أشهر إضافية.
That's very likely.
من المحتمل جدًا أن يكون ذلك.
And...
و...
The fee...
الرسوم...
It depends on how long the treatment goes on for.
يعتمد ذلك على المدة التي يستمر فيها العلاج.
But.
لكن.
It will still cost hundreds of thousands yuan.
وسيظل الأمر يكلف مئات الآلاف من اليوانات.
I undertand.
انا أفهم.
Thank you.
شكرًا لك.
Don't be worried.
لا تقلق.
The last words I said to my mother before I left were,
كانت آخر الكلمات التي قلتها لأمي قبل أن أرحل،
for her to pretend like she never had a daughter like me.
لتتظاهر وكأنها لم تنجب ابنة مثلي أبدًا.
Ever since I was old enough to understand,
منذ أن كنت كبيرًا بما يكفي لفهم،
my parents told me that,
لقد أخبرني والداي بذلك
girls should be ambitious,
ينبغي للفتيات أن يكن طموحات،
they should work hard.
ينبغي عليهم العمل بجد.
Only then will they be respected by others.
حينها فقط سوف يحظون بالاحترام من قبل الآخرين.
Only then will they have a good job.
حينها فقط سيكون لديهم وظيفة جيدة.
I have worked hard.
لقد عملت بجد.
Actually, I'm not particularly intelligent.
في الواقع، أنا لست ذكيًا بشكل خاص.
But I've tried my hardest.
ولكنني حاولت بكل ما أوتيت من قوة.
I managed to get to Beijing and attend university there.
تمكنت من الوصول إلى بكين والالتحاق بالجامعة هناك.
Graduated.
تخرجت.
Worked.
عملت.
Isn't that something to be proud of?
أليس هذا شيئاً يدعو للفخر؟
When I was in my third year,
عندما كنت في سنتي الثالثة،
my little brother got in to university too.
لقد التحق أخي الصغير بالجامعة أيضًا.
He was not good at studying.
لم يكن جيدا في الدراسة.
His tuition was very expensive.
كانت رسومه الدراسية باهظة الثمن.
My parents couldn't afford tuition for two people,
لم يتمكن والدي من تحمل تكاليف الدراسة لشخصين،
so I picked up a part-time job.
لذلك حصلت على وظيفة بدوام جزئي.
To earn money, to pay for my own fees.
لكسب المال، لدفع رسومي الخاصة.
After I started working,
بعد أن بدأت العمل،
All the money I earned, other than expenses like food and rent,
كل الأموال التي كسبتها، بخلاف النفقات مثل الطعام والإيجار،
I gave all the rest to my mother.
وأعطيت الباقي كله لأمي.
There's very little ignorance in you.
هناك القليل جدا من الجهل فيك.
My classmates gave me a nickname.
لقد أعطاني زملائي لقبًا.
They called me "Voldemort" [TN: A pun/slang for women who are devoted to their family]
لقد أطلقوا عليّ لقب "فولدمورت" [TN: تورية/عامية للنساء المخلصات لعائلاتهن]
Actually, I never thought
في الواقع، لم أفكر أبدا
that it was wrong to give the money I earned to my parents.
أنه كان من الخطأ أن أعطي المال الذي كسبته لوالديّ.
I don't think it's wrong for me to have a younger brother either.
لا أعتقد أنه من الخطأ أن يكون لي أخ أصغر أيضًا.
They're my kin.
إنهم أقاربي.
They are related to me by blood.
إنهم مرتبطون بي بالدم.
The closest people in the world.
أقرب الناس في العالم.
I try my best to be good to them.
أحاول أن أكون جيدًا معهم.
It's not wrong.
إنه ليس خطأ.
It's just that...
إنه فقط ذلك...
the biggest mistake is...
أكبر خطأ هو...
I was not chosen.
لم يتم اختياري.
It's not that I can't be good to my brother.
ليس الأمر أنني لا أستطيع أن أكون جيدًا مع أخي.
Why can't I be the one that was chosen?
لماذا لا أكون الشخص الذي تم اختياره؟